

💌 marcin@mm.st 🦸 martinrocker.com 🔲 marcinbiegun 🛅 mabiegun 🖸 spacecatlabs 🛗 Martin Rocker 3D

## Professional Summary \_\_\_\_\_

I'm a self-taught software developer generalist who enjoys solving complex problems with simple solutions.

I have 10 years of experience working as a software developer for webdev projects in multiple roles. 2020 was the year when I've decided to pivot my career towards more creative endeavors and started working as a game developer.

My current interests include but are not limited to 3D graphics, game mechanics, real-time audio-visual experiences, and procedural art creation. I still enjoy doing Linux and devops projects.

## Gamedev Skills \_\_\_\_\_

**Programming languages** C++, C#, Python, HLSL, GLSL

Developing gameplay systems and engine tools with C++, Blueprint scriptng, **Unreal Engine 5** 

materials, lights, VFX, animations, level building

Other technologies Unity3D

### **Tech Art Skills**

Creative toolkits TouchDesigner, Processing, JravaScript WebGL

Video Resolume, VDMX, Final Cut Pro X

3D Blender, Houdini, Notch Music Ableton Live, Fruity Loops

# Application Development Skills \_\_\_\_\_

**DevOps** Ubuntu, Proxmox, Ansible, AWS, Heroku

Databases PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Redis

**Backend** Ruby, Rails, Elixir, Phoenix, Go, GraphQL

Frontend HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

Mobile apps React Native

**Data processing** SQL, DBT, Jupyter, Spark

#### Education

#### **Silesian University of Technology**

Gliwice

B.S. IN MACROFACULTY OF ROBOTICS, ELECTRONICS AND INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES

Jul. 2006 - Nov. 2008

• Earned 75 ECTS credits towards a Master's Degree

# Training and courses \_\_\_\_\_

2022 **C++ Beyond Basics**, by Kate Gregory *Pluralsight.io* 

## **Work Experience**

Anshar Studios Katowice

C++ Developer, Unreal Engine Dec. 2020 -

- Worked on porting (an undisclosed) game from Untiy3D to Unreal Engine 5.
- · Developed gameplay features.
- · Created engine tools for game designers.

Codibly Kraków

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Apr. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- · Worked on a distributed Elixir/OTP application managing thousands of IoT devices in a renewable energy industry.
- Mentored colleagues new to functional programming and Elixir/OTP.
- Contributed to the backend application providing GraphQL API.
- Contributed to the frontend application written in Elm language.

Software Mansion Kraków

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Nov. 2019 - Apr. 2020

- Worked on a React Native application. Refactored old web JavaScript code, introduced a framework for sharing JavaScript between platforms.
- Developed a hardware-accelerated video encoding module for Membrane (media streaming framework) using Elixir and C++.

Contractbook Remote

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Oct. 2018 - Jul. 2019

- Delivered features in a large Elixir / Phoenix and JavaScript / React application.
- Designed, implemented and maintained a data processing pipeline used for processing user interaction and financial data. Built
  reports in Metabase.
- Cooperated in a multinational remote-first company.

#### **Social Drug Policy Initiative NGO**

Kraków

LEAD DEVELOPER Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Worked with the product owner and designers to translate the product vision into a product spec.
- Maintained ticket boards and specification documents.
- Set up server infrastructure and build system.
- Lead sprint meetings and managed the team of 3 junior developers working on a React Native mobile app and on Ruby backend service.

Relay That Remote

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Nov. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- · Worked with USA-based product owner on giving the product a new direction. Scoped projects, maintained task lists.
- Refactored a legacy Ruby on Rails codebase into a modern API service.
- Built a new frontend application in JavaScript and React.
- Built a JavaScript graphic composition library using modern CSS features.

Base CRM Kraków

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Nov. 2012 - Oct. 2016

- Delivered features in a complex architecture composed with dozens of Ruby microservices, large SQL and ElasticSearch databases, and RabbiMQ event queue.
- Worked closely with US-based finance and sales teams, gathered their requirements, wrote specifications, lead and coded the
  projects.
- Maintained a complex SASS pricing service, migrated to new pricing options.
- Built a system for collecting and processing financial data in Ruby, then migrated it to Apache Spark.
- Built an internal application for inspecting user data and running administrative actions.
- Lead a company-wide localization effort on multiple platforms.

Social Bicycles Kraków

MID DEVELOPER Nov. 2011 - Oct. 2012

- Developed an application for processing GSM communication between bikes and a server using ProtoBuf, Ruby, and RabbitMQ.
- Built an user-facing web application using Ruby on Rails and Backbone.js.

Left Brain Kraków

JUNIOR DEVELOPER Nov. 2010 - Oct. 2011

• Developed web applications using Ruby on Rails and MySQL.

Freelance Remote

Web Developer

Nov. 2008 - Oct. 2010

• Built websites using PHP Content Management Systems.